Osama Nusair

Nationality: Pakistani | Phone number: (+44) 7765171150 (Mobile) | Email address: xamaa6@gmail.com

Email address: osama.nusair@mail.bcu.ac.uk | Website: https://xamaa6.github.io/ | LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/xamaa6 | Address: 65 Tallington Road, B33 OPL, Birmingham, United Kingdom (Home)

ABOUT ME

A cyber security researcher/engineer with a passion for technology and a commitment to staying up-to-date with evolving digital world and its threat landscape. I bring a diverse range of skills, experience and knowledge that have been developed over the years through both my formal education and professional experience.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/02/2024 - 31/07/2024 Birmingham, United Kingdom

LAB DEMONSTRATOR BIRMINGHAM CITY UNIVERSITY

- Engaged with undergraduate students and practically demonstrated lab sessions
- Assisted students in Network Security labs
- Ethical Hacking tools and techniques with practical examples

01/03/2022 - 31/08/2023 Islamabad, Pakistan

FOUNDER AIROVERFLOW

- Conducted Vulnerability Assessment & Penetration Testing
 - Pakistan Bureau of Statistics
 - Ministry of Planning, Development & Special Initiatives
- Developed a prototype of Cyber Range
- Red Team Exercises
- Multiple workshops on Ethical Hacking & Defense
- Developed a Malware Analysis Tool in Sandbox Environment
- Conducted Pakistan Cyber Security Challenge (PCC) in 2022 & 2023

Email o.nusair@airoverflow.com | Website https://airoverflow.com/

01/08/2021 - 28/02/2022 Islamabad, Pakistan

COURSE INSTRUCTOR NATIONAL AND VOCATIONAL TECHNICAL TRAINING CENTRE (NAVTTC)

- Course Instructor
- Taught Ethical Hacking & Defense course to students from different backgrounds
- Following modules covered
 - Introduction to Linux
 - Network Scanning
 - · Penetration Testing tools & techniques
 - Intrusion Detection & Prevention Systems

01/02/2019 - 30/07/2021 Islamabad, Pakistan

RESEARCH ASSISTANT NATIONAL CENTRE FOR CYBER SECURITY (NCCS)

- Smartphone Digital Forensics Tool Development
- Worked on Android Digital Forensics tool development
- Developed iOS Forensics toolkit from scratch

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

18/09/2023 - 13/09/2024 Birmingham, United Kingdom

MSC CYBER SECURITY Birmingham City University

- Research and Development into Honeypots & Honeynets
- Honeypot strategies for edge network devices (Firewalls & VPN)
- Detection of multiple attack vectors using MITRE ATT&CK Threat Model

- Cyber Threat Intelligence (CTI) based on ENISA Threat Landscape

Website https://www.bcu.ac.uk/ | Thesis Honeypot Strategies for Edge Network Devices

05/09/2018 - 02/06/2022 Islamabad, Pakistan

BS CYBER SECURITY Air University, Islamabad

- Developed an indigenous security information & events management (SIEM) solution
- Log collection and parsing using agent based and agentless techniques
- Python as primary programming language. C# for windows agent
- Python Django for Web UI

Website https://www.au.edu.pk/ | Thesis Security Information & Events Management (SIEM)

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **URDU**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production Spoken interaction		
ENGLISH	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Cyber Security (Cryptography, IDS, HIDS, NAC, DLP e SIEM) | Digital Forensics | Cybersecurity | Vulnerability Assessment | Penetration Testing | Security Operations Center | Network Security | Linux | Endpoint Security | Web Application Security | Incident Response | Vulnerability Management | IT Security | Ethical Hacking | Malware Analysis | ISO 27001 | C / C# / C++ | Back-end (Flask, Django) | Intrusion Detection and Prevention System (IDS / IPS) | Linux (Red Hat, Debian) | Cyber Range | Capture The Flag (CTF) | Red Teaming

PROJECTS

07/2022 - 08/2023

Cyber Range

- Development of Cyber Range Platform for Red Team exercises
- Tools & Technologies:
 - Openstack
 - Kola Ansible
 - Google Cloud Platform (GCP)
 - Virtualization
 - Software Defined Networking (SDN)

02/2022 - 08/2022

Capture The Flag (CTF) Platform

- Capture The Flag (CTF) platform based on CTFd
- Organized multiple CTF events:
 - Pakistan Cyber Security Challenge (2022 & 2023)
 - Cyber Siege CTF (2022)
 - AirOverflow CTF (2024)

02/2020 - 03/2021

iOS Forensics

- Developed an extensive toolkit for iOS forensics
- Capable of live image acquisition
- Implementation of forensics analysis techniques
- Web frontend

01/2019 - 02/2020

Android Forensics

- Data recovery from android devices
- Digital Forensic imaging and preservation
- Filesystem analysis
- Automation of android root process

09/2019 - 02/2020

Ransomware Techniques in C++

- Developed techniques of ransomware in C++
- Implemented AES cryptographic algorithm for encryption / decryption

HONOURS AND AWARDS

Digital Pakistan Cybersecurity Hackathon - 2021

- Won first ever cyber security hackathon of Pakistan in two categories
- Network Attacks & Exploitation
- Speed Programming

President Air University Cyber Security Society

- Pioneer President of Air University Cyber Security Society (AUCSS)
- Led the society to achieve milestones
- Organized workshops
- Cyber Security Awareness talks and seminars

REFERENCES

Suleman Khan

Suleman Khan was my supervisor for digital forensics projects at National Centre for Cyber Security (NCCS).

Email Suleman.khan@liu.se | Phone (+46) 764320237

Dr. Kashif Kifayat

Dr. Kashif Kifayat was my supervisor for undergraduate final year project on Security Information and Events Management (SIEM) solution.

Email Dr.K.Kifayat@gmail.com | Phone (+44) 7984053307

Dr. Junaid Arshad

Dr. Junaid Arshad supervised my Master's Dissertation on Honeypot Strategies for Edge Network Devices.

Email junaid.arshad@bcu.ac.uk | Phone (+44) 7715986130